msgm.it 2018-12-22

# COOKIE POLICY | MSGM

Cookies are pieces of code stored in browser directories which assist the Owner in providing the service according to the purposes described. Some of the purposes of installation of Cookies may also require the consent of the User.

## What are cookies?

What are cookies? Cookies are small text-files that are memorized on the computer when a user visits a website. The text memorizes information that the website is able to read when it is accessed the second time. Some of these cookies are essential for a website to run correctly, while others are used to store information in a safe way, for instance, user names or language settings. The advantage of having cookies installed on your own pc is that you don’t need to re-enter the same authentication information every time you view a web page that you had viewed previously.

## Why does our site use cookies?

Our site uses cookies in order to provide users a customized buying experience which matches their tastes and preferences. Thanks to cookies, you won’t need to send or receive the saved information over and over. Cookies are used also for the optimization of the website’s performances: indeed, they speed up the purchase process, as well as they facilitate the research of specific contents within the site. In order to protect your own personal data against possible losses and any form of illicit treatment, we have taken appropriate technical and organizational measures. For further information, please refer to our Privacy policy.

## What cookies do we use and for what purpose?

Our website uses different types of cookies, each performing a specific function.

## Functional Cookies

These cookies are not necessary for the site to function, but provide a better surfing experience.

## Analytical cookies

These cookies are used, for instance, by Google Analytics in order to carry out statistical analyses of how users use our website through their computers or via our mobile applications, how many pages a user has visited or the number of mouse clicks made on a page while using the website. These analyses are processed in an anonymous way and for statistics purposes only, provided that the service supplier uses the cookies in connection with the browser installed on your computer or other device used to browse our website.

## Third-party cookies for marketing and retargeting

These cookies are used by third-party companies that we trust to show you advertising banners on other affiliate websites, featuring the latest products you have viewed on our site. While you are browsing our website, these cookies are also used to show you banners featuring products that you may be interested in, or similar to products you have previously viewed based on your browsing history. The usage of these cookies does not usually imply the processing of personal data but it may create a connection with your computer or other devices and track the information stored in it: these cookies are then connected to the browser installed on your computer or other device used during the navigation on our website.

## Social media cookies

These cookies allow your social account to interact with the website. They are used, for instance, to 'Like' or share contents with your friends on social networks. Social media cookies are not necessary for navigating the website.

## Technical and aggregate statistics cookies

## Activity strictly necessary for the website to function

This Application uses Cookies in order to save User session and to perform other activities that are strictly necessary for the usability of the website, for instance in relation to traffic distribution.

## Activity regarding the saving of preferences, optimization, and statistics

This Application uses Cookies to save browsing preferences and to optimize the User’s browsing experience. Among these Cookies are, for example, those to set the language and the currency or for the management of first party statistics employed directly by the Owner of the site.

## Other types of Cookies or third-party tools that might use them

Some of the services listed below collect statistics in aggregated form and may not require the consent of the User or may be managed directly by the Owner – depending on how they are described – without the help of third parties. If any third party operated services are listed among the tools below, these may be used to track Users’ browsing habits – in addition to the information specified herein and without the Owner’s knowledge. Please refer to the privacy policy of the listed services for detailed information.

## Interaction with social networks and external platforms

These services allow you to make interactions with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of the Application. Interactions and the information gained from this application are in any case subject to the User’s privacy settings related to each social network. If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

## Twitter social widget and Tweet button (Twitter)

The Twitter social widget and sharing buttons are social interaction services with the social network Twitter, provided by Twitter Inc.   
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage data.   
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

## Facebook social widgets and Like button (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook social widget and ‘Like’ button are services of interaction with the social network Facebook, provided by Facebook, Inc.   
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage data.   
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

## Google+ social widgets and +1 button (Google)

The Google+ social widget and +1 button are services of interaction with the social network Google+, provided by Google Inc.   
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage data.   
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/privacy/)

## Infrastructure monitoring

These services allow this Application to monitor the use and behavior of its components, so that its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved. Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, which by their nature filter the activities of this Application. 

**New Relic (New Relic)**   
New Relic is a monitoring service provided by New Relic Inc. New Relic is integrated in such a way to filter all traffic of this Application, i.e., communication between the Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data on this Application to be collected.  
Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://newrelic.com/privacy)

## Traffic distribution and optimization

These services allow this Application to distribute its contents through geographically distributed servers, as well as to optimize its performance. Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, which by their nature filter the activities between this Application and the User’s browser. Due to the distributed nature of this system, it is difficult to determine where contents – which might include the Personal Data of the User – are eventually transferred. 

**CloudFlare (CloudFlare)**   
CloudFlare is a Traffic distribution and optimization service provided by CloudFlare Inc. CloudFlare is integrated in such a way to filter all traffic of this Application, i.e., communication between the Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data on this Application to be collected.  
Personal Data collected: Cookie and Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy)

## Remarketing

These services allow this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User. This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity. 

**AdWords Remarketing (Google)**   
AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc., which connects the actions performed on this Application with the Google AdWords advertising network and Doubleclick Cookie.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

## Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior. 

**Google Analytics (Google)**   
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage data.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=it)

**Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google)**   
Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google, Inc. which connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Application.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/privacy/)

## Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them. If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it. 

**Youtube video widget (Google)**   
Youtube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/it/policies/privacy/)

**Vimeo, LLC**   
Content visualization service provided by external platforms. Vimeo is a video content visualization service provided by Vimeo, LLC that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy) – [Cookie Policy](https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy)

## Cookies that might be used

  * __utma / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * __utmb / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * __utmc / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * __utmz / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * __utmt / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * __utmv / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * _ga / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * _gat / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * NID / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * PREF / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * id / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * test_cookie / [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)
  * \--------------------
  * _js_datr / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * datr / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * locale / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * reg_ext_ref / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * reg_fb_gate / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * reg_fb_ref / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * wd / [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
  * \--------------------
  * \--------------------
  * PHPSESSID / [Multisafepay](https://www.multisafepay.com/)
  * \--------------------
  * \--------------------
  * PHPSESSID / this website
  * cb-enabled / this website
  * partner_ID / this website
  * _pop_code / this website
  * \--------------------
  * JSESSIONID / bam.nr-data.net
  * \--------------------

## How can I manage the installation of Cookies?

In addition to what is specified in this document, the User can manage preferences for Cookies directly from within their own browser and prevent – for instance – third parties from installing them. Through the browser preferences, it is also possible to delete Cookies installed in the past, including the Cookies that might possibly have saved the consent for the installation of Cookies by this website. It is important to note that by disabling all Cookies, the functioning of this site may be compromised. Users can find information about how to manage Cookies in their browser at the following addresses: [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=it&p=cpn_cookies), [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/it/kb/Attivare%20e%20disattivare%20i%20cookie?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Enabling+and+disabling+cookies), [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19214?viewlocale=it_IT&locale=en_US) e [Microsoft Windows Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/it-it/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies). In the case of services provided by third parties, Users can exercise their right to withdraw from the tracking activity by utilizing the information provided in the third party’s privacy policy, by clicking the opt out link – if provided – or by contacting the third party. Notwithstanding the above, the Owner informs that Users may take advantage of: [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). This service allows Users to select their tracking preferences for most of the advertising tools. The Owner thus recommends that Users make use of this resource in addition to the information provided in this document.

## How can I disable cookies in my browser?

It is possible to modify the settings of a browser so as to disable cookies. Please be aware: if you disable cookies your username and password will be no longer stored on the login box of the site. Most web browsers (Internet Explorer, Firefox, etc.) are configured to automatically accept cookies. However, most web browsers allow some control and disable cookies through the browser settings. Please note that disabling browsing cookies or functional cookies may prevent our website from functioning correctly and/or limit the services we offer.

To find out more about cookies, including how to manage and disable third-party or marketing/retargeting cookies, visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). Instead, in order to disable analytical cookies and to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, you can download the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser Add-on: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

## Google Chrome:

For more information please visit this [page](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en).

## Mozilla Firefox:

For more information please visit this [page](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences).

## Internet Explorer:

For more information please visit this [page](http://windows.microsoft.com/it-it/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies).

## Safari:

For more information please visit this [page](http://support.apple.com/).

## Safari iOS (mobile devices):

For more information please visit this [page](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677?utm_source=Agillic%20Dialogue).

## Opera:

For more information please visit this [page](http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/).

## Data Controller

## FFW srl - Via Mannelli 121/A 50132 Florence (Italy),

Since the installation of third party Cookies and other tracking systems through the services used within this Application can not be technically controlled by the Owner, any specific references to Cookies and tracking systems installed by third parties are to be considered indicative. In order to obtain complete information, please refer to the privacy policy for the respective third party services listed in this document. Given the objective complexity of the identification of technologies based on Cookies and their strict integration with the functioning of the Web, the User is invited to contact the Owner should he wish to receive any further information on the use of cookies and any use of the same – for example, by a third party – made through this website.

## Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies. This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.

This page is visible through the link at the bottom of all the pages of the Site in accordance with article 122, second paragraph of Legislative Decree n.196/2003 and following the simplified information norms and acquisition of consent to the use of cookies published on the Official Gazette n.126 of 3rd June, 2014 and its record of the action n. 229 of 8th May, 2014.

Last modified: 1st June, 2015
